Welcome to San Francisco,
the city by the bay --
Home to 30,000 fire hydrants,
4 million tennis balls,
and very liberal
pooper scooper laws.
My name is lucky.
I'm a dog,
in case you hadn't guessed,
and I belong to this man.
You remember Dr. dolittle,
right?
The guy who can talk
to animals?
If you don't,
let me jog your memory.
He's a doctor,
and he talks to animals.
Well, anyway,
he's busier than ever.
- Doctor.
- Yes.
You've got Mr. Carson
at 10 for a full workup.
Mr. wennington's e.K.G.'S
at 12.
Mrs. bloom called.
She got a bad rash on her back.
- I told her 11:15.
- Okay, got you.
Buster's deworming is at 12:30.
Misty's kennel cough is back.
I put her in at 1. Afternoon
wall-to-water neuters.
You've got the rotary club
dinner tonight.
You've got the kennel club
breakfast tomorrow.
Okay, push Mr. Carson's workup
to 11.
- I will deworm Buster at 12,
do the e.K.G. -30.
Move misty to 1:15,
and, look, lucky,
you've gotta stop mixing up
my charts.
Last week you almost had me
neuter Mr. panitch.
Oh, yeah, well,
from what I hear,
you'd be doing Mrs. panitch
a favor.
Anytime, ladies. Thank you.
No matter how busy he got,
doc always found time
to help animals.
Hi. My name is bandit.
- Hi, bandit.
How you doin', bandit?
And I'm a stray.
- That's okay.
- We're all strays.
I know how hard it is
the first time
to get up there, bandit.
Take your time.
- Just one paw at a time, bandit.
- That's true.
That's right.
Never give up hope, bandit.
Never ever give up hope,
and not just bandit.
All you dogs, listen to me.
Every dog in here can find
a family
and be somebody's best friend.
- Mm-hmm.
- Let me hear you say that.
Say,
"I am somebody's best friend."
I am somebody's best friend.
One more time again.
"I am somebody's best friend!"
I am somebody's best friend!
That's right. That's right.
Also, there's a family
out in north beach
that's trying to find
a good watchdog --
Somebody that's housebroken
and great with kids.
Any of you guys got a background
in security?
Oh, that'd be rusty.
Rusty's a watchdog.
Who's rusty?
- Rusty, tell -- oh, no.
- Rusty.
This better be important.
No, uh, never mind, rusty.
Every zoo in the country
had a job for the doc.
He was especially good
at matters of the heart.
So how long has it been
since you guys made
little baby turtles?
Not that long,
maybe 20 years.
It'll be 48 years
next Monday.
Okay, I see --
I see the problem here.
I know what to do.
But, listen,
I'm gonna give you
these pills.
I want you to crush 'em up
and put 'em in your food.
Oh, yeah? What do they do?
Ah, yeah, you're lookin' fine.
Comin' at ya, baby.
In fact, he became
an international celebrity,
traveling from Alaska
to Australia.
I'm here with
the world-famous Dr. dolittle,
who actually
speaks with animals.
Now, what we're gonna do is
sneak up on
and rescue this
unsuspecting alligator.
We'll have to be quiet
so he doesn't know we're here.
The trick with catching
this alligator
is to be wary of
those teeth -- huge great...
Hey, dude, see, what I'm doing
is allowing Steve to think
that I don't know
he's back there,
wait until he tries to grab me,
turn on him
and, Bob's your Uncle,
bite his arm off.
I'm gonna have to get my arm
'round his neck and hang on --
- Steve, I think he knows
we're over --
-shh!
I don't wanna blow the element
of surprise.
Now!
- Oh! Oh!
- Crikey, me arm!
Yeah, it seemed everybody
wanted a piece
of the good doctor,
and his family understood.
- Thank you.
- Well, most of them did.
But we'll get to that part
in a minute.
- Thank you very much!
- Right now
I gotta answer the door.
Uh...
Yeah, who's there?
Hey, it's me. I forgot my key.
Open up.
Well, then I guess
you'll have to beg, huh?
Ha! Come on, boy, beg.
Come on.
Get it? Role reversal.
'Cause usually it's the human
that says to the dog, uh...
I know you better open u
p the door 'fore I...
Just open the door, lucky.
Seeing as you're the one
who feeds me,
I'm gonna let you in
this time.
Okay. Thank -- thank you.
Thank you.
Guess who's back
from France!
- John?
- Hey!
- Hey, sweetie.
- How you doin'? Ohh!
Mmm!
I got you a present
from Paris.
- That's for me?
- Yes, that's for you, for us.
Really? Oh!
Yeah, I can enjoy this present
as well.
You know what would be a really
nice present, John, though?
- What's that?
- If you could keep that flock
of your faithful
away from the door.
- I'm sorry.
I'll talk to them later, okay?
- Daddy!
- Hey, baby. How you doin'?
Hi. Hey, look, I got you
a little present from Mexico.
- Gracias.
- Yeah.
Ooh, I wonder what it is.
Hey, earthquake! 9-1-1!
Nuevo-uno-uno!
Oh, no, no, don't shake it.
I wouldn't shake it.
Ow! My spleen!
Ooh, that hurt.
- Oh!
- He's cute! Thanks, dad!
Hey,
this isn't puerto vallarta.
It's a chameleon.
You know, it can change color
against different backgrounds
you put it on.
The blendmaster is in the house.
I'm gonna disappear
like old baby's daddy.
Now you see me...
Boom! Now you don't, eh?
- No, we can still see you.
- I'm not gone?
I'm not invisible?
Uh, you did remember
it's charisse's birthday?
Sure. Did you remember
to get the cake from stenson's?
Uh, actually,
charisse doesn't wanna have
a family birthday party.
What's that about? I thought
we always celebrate together.
- Okay, you have anything green,
maybe?
- Hey.
- Take this thing to your room,
please.
- Lettuce. Guacamole?
A zucchini? A big pickle?
- She's got a date.
- I suck.
A date? A date with who?
I didn't ask.
She's a big girl now, John.
Well, we'll see
about this date thing.
Where's
the birthday girl at?
Uh, she's unreachable.
What do you mean,
she's unreachable? Where is she?
She's in her room with the door
locked and headphones on.
You could try paging her.
She's in the house,
and she's unreachable?
In the house
with her headphones,
and I'm supposed to page her
in my house?
I'm-a page somebody
in my own house?
Okay, we'll see
if I'm-a page someone.
I ain't paging nothin'.
Careful, doc, she's 16.
That's a tough age.
Hey! Charisse, open this door!
Do you believe this?
- Hey!
- Try her cell.
I'm not calling on the cellphone
while she's in her bedroom.
Hey! Charisse!
Open the door!
Okay. All right. Okay!
Okay!
Charisse!
Those teenagers, doc.
They can drive a man
to drink.
Hey.
What are you drinkin'?
Gatorade.
- Oh, really? Give it to me.
- Hmm.
Gatorade make wine now, huh?
- Uhh...
- You better slow down.
Which one of you is dolittle?
What now?
I have a message from the boss.
From the who?
The boss. The godbeaver.
Now save the questions
and come with me.
You guys know the rules.
You just don't come up here
on my balcony.
Make an appointment.
You make an appointment!
Now go! You tell the beaver
to make an appointment
just like everybody else.
I can't tell him that. I'll end
up sleeping with the fishes.
How's it gonna look in the paper
if Dr. dolittle
throws a possum off the roof?
That's not gonna look right.
- Now leave. 'Cause I will.
- Watch your tone, buddy.
Charisse!
Talk.
- This is daddy. How are you?
- Hey!
I got a couple of questions
for you.
I wanna know how come I gotta
climb up a side of a building...
- Dad, dad, calm down.
I can't understand a word...
- And get on a cellphone
to talk to you in your bedroom!
- Dad, where are you?
Dad!
Dad, what are you doing?
What?! What am I doing?
Because this is the only way
I can reach you!
What are you doin' in here?
What's all of this?
What's all of that about? You
don't do that in public, do you?
Dance? Of course.
That's not dancing.
That's advertising.
And what's this about you don't
wanna spend your birthday
with your family?
Dad, having dinner
with your family
is what you do when
you're young,
not when you're turning 16.
Besides, I have a date.
Well, you can bring
your date with you,
'cause you're coming to dinner.
- Oh, cool!
"Eric, these are my parents
and my little sister.
They're gonna be joining us
on our date."
No, he's gonna be joining us
at a family event, charisse.
We have it every year.
I don't even know why...
- What's this?
- Dad, that's private.
I can see why it's private.
It's embarrassing, charisse.
You got two c's
and a d on here.
Embarrassing?
Dad, you are the last person
who should be talking about
anything being embarrassing.
What are you talkin' about?
What's that supposed to mean?
Aah!
Oh, so I'm supposed to stop
doing what I do,
stop doing my work
and stop helping animals
because
you find it embarrassing?
That's not gonna happen.
That's right. It's not gonna
happen, so forget about it.
You're comin' to dinner.
Look at this.
No cellphone for a week.
Oh, what am I gonna do
without my cellphone?
Here are some stamps.
You can learn to write a letter
to somebody or something.
You think I care? Look at me.
Do I look like I care?
Look, just take --
Do I look like I --
Look at me.
No, charisse, look at me.
Do I look like I care?
Look. I don't care.
This is unbelievable. You know,
she has 50 numbers in here.
- Not one of 'em is mine.
- You shouldn't be looking
at that.
Why not?
"Biggie mack cell."
"Biggie mack pager."
"Biggie mack home."
- Who the hell is biggie mack?
- I don't know, John.
I'm gonna find out
who biggie mack is.
I don't like that name.
Biggie mack. What the hell
kind of name is that?
What is that?
Marcus's cellphone.
- Cellphone?
- Mm-hmm.
- When did he get a cellphone?
- Last week.
- What are you doing?
- Shh!
- John!
- Shh! I'm checking out
biggie mack.
Hello?
Hey, who is this?
Well, who is this?
Is this biggie mack?
Who wants to know?
Hey, I'm asking the questions
here, punk!
- What?!
- How old are you?
None of your damn business.
Oh, really, what if I make it
my business to find out
how old you are?!
- Are you threatenin' me?!
No, I don't make threats!
I'm promisin' you
that if you ever --
-is this John dolittle?
- Hi. I'm so sorry.
That's a wrong number.
That's a grown man that's on
the other end of that phone.
I wish I could say
the same thing about you.
The door.
- I hear the door.
- Go get that door right now!
Who am I, Mr. French
up in here?
- Honestly.
- I got to get doors?
Hey, Dr. d! Whassup?
It's me.
Me? Who's me? Back up, me.
I'm sayin',
you gonna let me in?
Dr. d, what's goin' on?
Excuse me?
Remember me? Eric.
Domino's pizza?
Extra cheese, anchovies,
tomatoes, guacamole...
- Pizza. You're the pizza guy.
- Yeah, I delivered that.
Well, thanks a lot, man. What,
did I forget to give you a tip?
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, no, that's cool.
No, you gave me somethin'
a little better than a tip.
I'm gonna take care of you, man,
'cause, you know,
it's nice to have a little --
- hey, Eric.
Whassup, baby?
What's going on? You ready?
Whoa, whoa, wait.
This is your date?
Dad, Eric. Eric, dad.
Ha ha. My man.
Whassup? Whassup?
Um, Eric, mm, no.
We have to stay here
with the family and eat dinner.
Huh?
It's cool with me.
Hey, charisse,
now don't be like that.
You're gonna ruin dinner
for everybody.
Come on, now.
You know what, pops?
Don't even sweat that, man.
Don't worry. I know how
to take care of this.
Pops?
You know, charisse has always
had a mind of her own.
When she was
about a year and a half,
she decided she wasn't gonna
wear diapers anymore.
- Remember that?
- John.
She started having
all these little accidents
around the house 'cause
she didn't have it down yet.
So we'd have little piles
of stuff -
dad, you just had to go there,
didn't you?
Come on, this is family.
We're talking about old days.
It's cool. It's cool.
I'm actually learnin' something.
Really?
You're learning something?
You know what's interesting?
You never learned to take off
your hat at the dinner table.
- Isn't your head getting hot?
- Sorry.
I know mine is getting hot
just sitting here
lookin' at you in that hat.
16. Just think, charisse,
in 2 years,
you'll be out of this house
and on your way to college.
One year, 10 months, 16 days.
You know what? Berkeley's
a really close college.
If you went to Berkeley,
you could live at home
and you could save money.
That's a good idea, but I've
already reserved a u-haul
for the day I graduated
high school.
Oh, you've reserved a u-haul
already?
Uh, dad,
someone to see you.
Yo. Step outside.
Thank you, sweetie.
- Excuse me, darling.
- Bye, dad. Love you.
I love you, too.
Excuse me, Eric.
- Yeah.
- Hey, yo, yo, down here.
- Okay.
- All right,
now, what do you want?
First of all, let me say,
the beaver sends
birthday greetings
to your lovely daughter.
Oh, really?
That's very nice.
Now you go and you tell
the beaver
he's starting to get
on my nerves.
Oh, why you gettin'
bent out of shape for?
He only wants a moment
of your time.
- What if I say no?
- I don't think you wanna go down
that road, my friend.
All right, look, you go
and tell the beaver
8:00, my office, tomorrow.
Oh, the beaver don't travel
for nobody.
He knows you're a busy man,
and he'll remember this,
but this is truly
a life or death situation.
All right, shut up. Listen.
My car, 7 A.M. in the morning.
- All right?
- Hey, this is good news.
The beaver likes good news.
Thank you.
Jimmy, get the car!
Come on, blow your candles out
and make a wish.
- Whee! Surprise!
- Happy Birthday!
There's a mouse in the house!
- Hey, give me that.
- I am licking the candles.
Oh, yeah? Well, you can lick
my fat, funky, little --
Hey, don't be a piggy.
Charisse, I'm so sorry.
Ooh! Ooh! Hey, watch the fur.
Watch the fur, buddy.
We're trying to do somethin'
nice for your daughter.
I bet if a cute little kitty
popped out,
you'd say "oh, how cute.
How cute."
- But you're not. You're not.
- Put me down! I wanna --
Listen, you're not a couple of
cute little kitties.
- Yes, we are.
- You're two disgusting rats...
- No, we're not.
- That just ruined
the birthday cake.
Oh, so you wanna get
personal now?
Well, you know what "rats"
spelled backwards is, mister?
It's "star!" That's right.
I'm a star, buddy.
Oh, really, is that right?
Well, do you know what "ha"
spells backwards?
Uh, no, I don't have --
Ah!
Exactly!
Could it be? Yes, it is!
- Diapers!
- And my favorite -- chocolate.
Say "Maya."
Maya.
- Maya.
Um, what do you think
you're doing?
I think he's about to say
something.
Bring me a bone.
And a large order of flies.
Supersized.
You will be bring me ham,
luncheon meats, cold cuts.
Lucky, out.
Hey, Maya, can I talk to
charisse alone a second?
Okay. Come on, boy.
Hey, charisse, look,
I'm sorry about tonight.
Okay, I'm thinking
about cutting back a little bit
and spending some more time
around here with you guys.
Great. Now more
animals will be here.
What if we don't stay here?
We can go on a big vacation
to Europe, the whole family.
- What about that?
- Are you serious?
I'm dead serious.
We can go to Paris, Rome.
The Greek islands.
We always talked about that.
Let's do it.
What do you think?
Is this a bribe?
Yes, this is a bribe.
It's working.
Hey, yo, doc, one other thing
I forgot to tell --
- Tomorrow!
- What?
- Jeez.
- Tomorrow.
- Yeah.
European vacation. So, tomorrow.
Tomorrow we're going to Europe!
Tomorrow.
So doc, the raccoon,
and the possum took a road trip
to meet
this mysterious beaver.
Hey, doc, nice wheels.
What do you call this thing?
Oh, this is a mustang.
Yo, doc, is there a car
named after me?
No, I don't think
they make a possum.
Why not?
Not a lot of cars named
after rodents.
All right, I wanna go over
a couple of ground rules
for when you're
in the beaver's presence.
Number one --
No sudden movements.
Number two --
Do not stare at his teeth.
Between you and me, he's got
a little bit of an overbite.
I personally think he needs
braces, but I'm not a dentist.
Numbers 3 through 10 --
You'll treat him with
the respect he deserves.
Capisce?
We're talkin'
about a beaver, right?
Hey, tootie, how you doin'?
How's it hanging?
Hey, doctor, how are you?
Hey, back away. Back away
from him, Jimmy, all right?
Show some respect,
you animals.
Excellent.
The raccoon got the doctor.
He says
he's a miracle worker.
- Hello?
- Hey, Paulie,
get the boss ready.
Doin' everythin' you say,
Joey.
Doin' everythin' like
you told me.
I'm just --
I'm gonna go get some acorns.
Yeah, Dr. dolittle, I presume.
Welcome to my den.
Would you like a fish?
Oh. No, thank you.
I've eaten already.
Hey, the beaver offers you
a fish, you take the fish.
- Joey, shut up.
- Sorry, boss.
I've heard good things
about you
from some of
the bay area families.
From the bay area families?
Really??
What are you guys, some kind
of mafia or something?
Mafia? No. We don't know nothin'
about no mafia. Do we, boys?
- Nah, never heard of it.
- No, that's a myth.
I'm just a simple fisherman
who's blessed with many friends.
Perhaps you'll be one of them.
What do you guys want
from me?
Well, I'm losin'
my territory.
The other animals movin' in
on you or somethin'?
Yeah. The human kind.
They're cuttin' down our homes,
bustin' up families.
Word is, they're cuttin' down
the whole forest.
Okay, guys, you're talking
to the wrong person.
You need to contact
one of those nature groups
like the Sierra club
or, um...
It has to be you, doc.
You're the only one who knows
how to speak human.
Yeah, we can't fight humans
on our own.
I mean, they got guns and knives
and pullout couches.
Sure, I got rabies.
I could bite somebody.
But I can only do so much.
You guys have no idea
what I'm talking about, do you?
Sure, I do.
It's man against nature.
But with you on our side,
I like the odds.
Me on your side? I didn't say
I was gonna help you.
I didn't say.
Doctor, before you say no,
I would like you to see what
we're talkin' about.
It's gone.
Everything gone.
How do you save a forest,
anyway?
You know, it's not
gonna be easy, John.
I would assume the lumber
companies have a lot of clout.
But I do know, if there were
a threatened
or an endangered species
living in the forest,
there definitely are laws
that protect it.
How am I gonna find out
if any endangered animals
are in the forest?
Well...
You could ask Eugene.
We found
an endangered species of bear,
a female whose mother
had been killed by poachers.
She's the only pacific
Western bear up there.
Well, that's good. One bear has
to be protected, right?
Well, no. The lawyers for
Potter's logging company argued
that since she's the only one
up there,
there's no chance for survival
of the species anyway.
- There'd have to be a male, too.
- Pardon me.
Why don't we just get a male
up there,
get the two of them together,
and let nature take its course?
- If I may...
- Well, unfortunately,
the only male
pacific Western bear...
- Psst!
That we could find
was raised in captivity.
- Excuse me.
- Never been bear raised
in captivity
that's been successfully
reintroduced to the wild.
They've never had
the world-famous love doctor
makin' the introductions.
- Psst! Doctor.
- Excuse me a second.
Your man left the barn door
open.
- Somethin' wrong?
- Uh, the, uh...
Oh, jeez. Hope that bamm-bamm
didn't see that.
No, I'm sure. The giraffe is
the one that was disgusted.
- I am so sorry.
- Yeah.
I know you're really
disappointed.
Disappointed?
About not going to Europe?
Now, dad, why would I be
disappointed?
I made you a promise.
I'm gonna stick to it.
If you don't want me to do this,
I'll understand, okay?
I can actually say no
and not feel guilty
for the rest of my life?
When do we leave?
As soon as we can get a court
order to stop the clearcutting.
Who's gonna argue the case?
Wh-why you lookin' around?
Me?
What "me"? Not me. You.
- No, no, no.
- Yes, yes, yes.
- No, no, no, no.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes.
- No.
- Come on, sweetie.
For the animals.
- Don't make me do this.
- For the animals.
For the animals.
- For the animals?
- Do it for the animals.
- I don't do animal law.
That's specieism.
You're a specieist.
No, your honor.
We're simply asking
for an injunction
so that we might have the chance
to save a species.
Your honor, this is a delaying
tactic/publicity stunt.
Saving a species.
I have affidavits signed
by a range of experts
who all concur
that to take a bear raised
in captivity
and reintroduce it
into the wild
is, well, dangerous
and irresponsible.
Simply put,
a bear raised by "circus folk"
wouldn't know how to feed itself
or interact with real bears,
let alone make it through
its first winter.
No. It would certainly succumb
to Darwin's law of nature --
Survival of the fittest.
Actually --
Well, yeah,
but Darwin's never met my dad.
Young lady,
that's inappropriate behavior.
And just who is your father?
Sir, your honor, that's me.
I'm her father. Name's dolittle.
Dr. dolittle.
Dr. dolittle?
Do you feel you could
rehabilitate a tame bear
and mate it in the wild
with a female?
Yes, I do, your honor.
In that case, I'll grant
a one month's delay
on the harvesting
of Campbell's grove.
For one month, Dr. dolittle.
That's it.
Thank you, sir.
And, doctor, if that bear
should so much as set one paw
in a campsite or this town,
I'll rescind this order
immediately.
I understand completely.
Thank you, your honor.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, your honor.
Dr. dolittle, over here!
Dr. dolittle, you speak to both
domestic and wild animals.
Can the circus bear relate
to a forest bear?
Well, I don't know much
about him,
except that he's been
living in captivity,
so I'm sure he'll be really
happy to return to the wild.
So much for a family vacation.
But doc figured,
how hard could this be?
That was before he met Archie.
Ladies and gentlemen,
he's the bear with flair,
the walkin' rug
with an adorable mug --
Archie the bear!
They love me. Go.
Archie! Archie!
Whew, big-boned gal, huh?
Yeah, I guess so.
You got any action shots?
You know what I'm talkin' 'bout.
No, I don't, but listen,
you'd be really lucky to wind up
with somebody like her.
Oh, look, I have had so many
girlfriends, you know.
Okay, look, I've never had
a girlfriend,
but just bring her by.
Bring her by on Monday.
That's when I'm dark, okay?
Oh, no, no, no,
I can't bring her here.
- You have to go to her.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Go to her? Where?
- Um, she's in the forest.
Ooh, uh,
I don't play forests.
I'm strictly state fair,
small arena type bear.
Archie, do you know
what kind of bear you are?
Um, let's see. Yes.
I'm a singer, dancer,
three years' tap,
two years jazz...
No, Archie,
you're an endangered species.
Hey, is that a threat, buddy?
Because my lawyer
will be down here --
It's not a threat.
I'm not threatening you.
What I'm saying is that
you're a very rare bear.
You're what's called
a pacific Western bear.
- You know what that is?
- Yes. I know.
Look, I can play
any kind of bear.
I've got range --
Grizzly, panda, polar.
Check out my polar --
"I am freezing! It is cold!"
Okay, I haven't made it
clear enough.
Let me break it down to you.
Your ancestors come from
the mountains of California.
- Yes, blah, blah, blah.
- When you were 6 months old,
they took you from your mother
and they taught you
to wiggle your hips to
a recording of "hound dog."
peace and quiet. No, no.
No, I taught myself that.
I admit, I pander 'cause
I'm a pander bear! Get it?
- Pander bear.
- Yes, funny stuff, Archie.
But listen,
what I'm proposing to you
is I'd like to take you
back to where
your ancestors roamed,
get you out in the woods
and teach you to be
a real bear.
Look, I like the bear I am,
okay? I'm famous.
Look, have you been
in the gift shop?
I have my own beanie baby.
You do this, I promise,
you'll be the most famous bear
in all the world.
- Bigger than pooh?
- Are you kiddin' me?
You pull this off, they'll be
sayin' "winnie the who?"
You've got yourself a bear.
And in what must be one
of the most unusual stories
of the year,
Dr. John dolittle is trying
to rewrite the laws of nature
by attempting to reintroduce
a performing bear into the
wild.
And, in doing so,
he hopes to save an entire
forest from destruction.
It's Darwin versus dolittle.
Oh, get over yourself.
Governor, I've got two lumber
mills waiting for that wood.
I understand, Joe,
but it's complicated,
especially if that
endangered bear survives.
If I don't meet my quota,
governor,
you're the one
who's gonna be in danger.
Now, now, j.P. Not to worry.
That ridiculous bear is bound
to screw up at least once.
And when he does, you'll have
yourself a new trophy.
And I've got just the place
to put him.
So we all moved to the forest
and waited for Archie
to arrive.
Now, while the family
got settled,
it was time I started
looking out for number one.
Ha ha! Ah?
Well, this looks like it's as
good a place as any here.
Here we go. Ah.
The simple pleasures of life.
Holy lord.
That wolf is a fox.
I hope I don't have dog breath,
you know, from licking my own...
Never mind.
Oh, you like that, ah?
Yeah, that was me.
Ha ha ha.
Plenty more where that came
from, you know what I mean?
Ha ha.
Grr to you, too.
What is that? Some kind of
secret wild lady dog code
for "you like me"?
Yeah, I do some dancing.
Here's a little move I call
the back scratcher.
Pretty cool, huh?
Hey, hot lady dog, wait.
Where are you goin'?
Call me!
And so the big day finally came
and I had a feeling the fur
was gonna fly.
Okay, everybody,
you all know why we're here.
We're about to try to do
something
that's never been done before.
And everyone thinks that we
can't pull this off,
and they got
their blades sharpened
and their trucks ready to roll.
But we're gonna prove 'em wrong,
right?
That's right. I want everybody
to put their claws together
and how about a big round
of applause
for the bear that's gonna lead
the way?
Let's hear it for Archie!
Yeah!
Come on!
Are you ready
to save the forest?!
Well, put your paws up.
Put your paws up.
Come on, now.
- Put...
- Is this some kind of joke?
Hey, I wanna go serious on you
for a second.
I know I've got my work
cut out for me,
but with your help,
I know one thing.
Now. Go.
Everybody!
We're dead.
Never more.
This show's over.
Well, let's go fool around.
You got your work cut out
for you, doc.
Okay, I'm done. That's good.
Turn it off.
You're not a real bear.
You're Wayne Newton
in a bear suit.
It's so dirty.
Look at my paws.
Yes, it's the woods, Archie.
Its chief component is dirt.
Wait. Hey, doc, is that her?
She's a babe.
- Yeah, that's her.
- Oh, look at the way she moves.
Oh, man.
I'll tell you what. I'm gonna go
over there and introduce you.
- You just wait here, okay?
- Yeah, good.
Hey, tell her I really dig her
fat pouch, but don't be crude.
- I'll try to work that in.
- Okay. Good.
Wait. Hey. God.
Oh, are you coming over here?
I'm a little busy...
Foraging.
- Hi.
Hello. My name is John.
- I'm Ava.
- Hi, Ava.
That's a pretty name, Ava.
Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
- Hey. Quick question, Ava.
How would you like to meet
the man of your dreams?
You're real cute,
but I don't go interspecies.
Oh, no.
I'm not talking about me.
I'm talking about --
I shouldn't have said "man."
- Oh.
- I should've said "bear."
- Okay.
- How would you like to meet
the bear of your dreams?
Look at that big --
What do you think
of that big, magnificent
hunk of bear over there?
Um, I don't think I see him.
Oh, is he standing
behind that dork?
Oh, no, he is...
Look, let me explain to you
what's going on, all right?
There's a logging company
that's gonna tear down
this whole forest -- everything.
- Oh.
- And the only thing that can
stop 'em
is if I can get two
pacific Western bears together.
You're a pacific Western bear,
and so is he.
And if I can get
the two of you together,
and you made little
pacific Western bears, then...
You see where I'm going
with this?
Uh-huh, yeah. Look, no offense,
but I don't talk to bear pimps.
Hey, wait a minute.
At least let me call him over
so you can meet him,
please?
Hey, Archie, come over here.
Hey, Johnny, there you are.
Come on, man, I thought we could
go work out. Jeez.
- Okay, Archie, you're on.
- What do I say to her?
Get to know her a little bit.
Tell her a little
about yourself.
Hi, I'm Archie.
I like moonlit walks
on the beach,
uh, sharing slop buckets
with that special someone
and soulful sounds
of the backstreet boys.
You're very weird.
Weird as in sexy?
No, just... Weird.
Hey, Archie, Archie, uh,
why don't you let me take it
from here?
- That was good.
- Okay.
Damn!
So, Ava, what do ya
think of Archie? Cute, huh?
- Oh, don't make me eat you.
- Stop that.
I know he's a little
uncomfortable
around the female species
at first, but if you give --
That's not even really
the point.
See, I need a real bear --
Someone who can hunt and protect
and provide for me.
Oh. Okay, I can understand that.
Yeah.
And, you know, I'm already
involved with someone.
Really?
You have a boyfriend already?
- A bearfriend.
- Yeah.
Are you in love
with this bear?
Love? Look,
my cousin married for love.
And the next thing she knows,
he's two-timing her
with this hot little grizzly
in a cave up north.
- Okay, so you're not in love?
- No.
All right, let's make a deal.
Don't make any decisions
for a month.
I'm gonna go work
with Archie.
In a month's time, I'm gonna
turn that bear into a bear
that you will be proud to have
little bear cubs with, okay?
Check it out!
I've flipped for you!
Pine cone.
- Hey.
- Hey. Mm.
Mm.
Perfect night.
Mm-hmm.
Sittin' out here, breathin'
this fresh country air,
and just listenin' to
the crickets chirp.
Yup.
Hey, you know what the crickets
are saying?
Dad, I don't know what
the crickets are saying.
I don't speak to the animals.
You're the one
who understands them, not me.
Little monkeys don't come up to
me and ask me for a 40 ounce.
I don't say "can I help you,
little animal?"
Do you need a shot?"
I don't do that, dad.
- Hey.
- I'm up in my room,
listening to music.
- Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Do you see me talking
to the animals?
Hey, hey. Slow it down
a second now.
I was just gonna tell you
that the crickets are nature's
thermometers. That's all.
Now you can tell how cold it is
by how fast they chirp.
Okay.
It seems a little cold out here,
doesn't it?
Yeah. A little nippy.
Maybe I need to go get
my vest. Yeah.
Oh!
Yo, fake Dr. dre and snoop,
man.
Hey. Hey, get a tune-up, man.
Get a tuneup.
Yo, whassup, baby?
Hey, Eric.
Mmm!
Hey! Hey!
You left your homie!
- Whassup, Dr. d?
- I don't know, Eric.
Maybe you should tell me
what's up.
Yo, man, I came to visit.
I figured
since y'all love me so much,
that I was gonna stay
a couple days, if it was cool.
Oh, no, no. Hell, no.
Charisse, I don't understand.
What's not there to understand,
dad?
Um, Eric with bags.
I don't understand that.
Well, he's staying here
for a couple nights.
- Mama said so.
- Oh, your mother said so.
- Yes, mom.
- Oh, okay, Eric,
you're gonna have to be on
the floor in the living room
in a sleeping bag
on the floor,
if you don't have a problem
with that.
Uh, and, by the way, Eric,
I'm watching you.
And not just me. You know,
I got eyes all around the woods.
You know, I talk to
the birds, right?
- Thanks, dad.
- Yes.
- Watch your back.
- I hear you.
- Yeah, you feel me?
- Yeah, I feel you.
Okay. All right. I'm watching!
I'm watching you, Eric.
I'm watching your back!
Bears are opportunistic eaters,
finding food wherever
they can...
Can we please see
what else is on?
No, we can't see
what else is on.
You need to watch this,
Archie,
to learn how to feed yourself
and survive during the winter.
What is he doing, diggin'?
You never even wondered
what your sharp claws
was for, have you?
Uh, no.
Bears are excellent swimmers.
Not this bear.
I know you're not gonna sit
there and tell me
you don't know how
to swim.
Wait, you haven't heard?
There's a new invention.
It's called... The boat.
Okay, that's the last straw.
Tomorrow morning, we're gonna
get up at the crack of dawn
and I'm teaching you
how to fish.
How about noonish?
Unbelievable.
And so began the bearathon,
a training mission so grisly,
so unbearable, so hairy...
Okay, that's enough.
All right, Archie,
let's do it.
This river's full of fish.
Let's go.
Yup. So is red lobster.
Hey, don't look at me.
Look at the water.
That's where the fish are.
They're moving.
Oh, man, one just touched me!
- What just touched me?
- Look, you big furry baby,
I want you to put your face
down in that water right now
and grab a fish!
- No.
- Archie, I want you to do
just like you saw on TV.
Put your face under the water
and catch a fish.
You can do it! Come on, man.
I'm here with you.
Go under the water.
All right! I'll try it.
All right. 1, 2, 3.
That's it!
That's Archie.
- Whassup?
Oh, fellas, whassup?
Okay. Okay, get one.
Archie!
Hey! Archie! Archie!
Okay, Archie, now you tell me
how smart you have to be
to lift your head out of the
water when you can't breathe.
I saw a light.
It was a bright light.
It was beautiful.
Okay, that's it. We're gonna
take you on
a little trip right now that's
gonna toughen you up.
- Come on.
- What? What?
We're gonna find something
even you can catch. Come on.
I saw my grandma.
Go on, eat.
- Oh. I...
- Come on, eat.
They're --
I don't eat the...
I'm good, thanks.
Okay, am I close?
Cold.
Use the force.
Colder? Warmer? Arctic.
So, how's it going?
I think it's going great.
I'm not even gonna need
three weeks.
Honey, look, he's already
foraging grapes, right?
Why's he walkin' away
from 'em?
He's not walkin' away from them.
He's circling the grapes.
Why?
Are they dangerous grapes?
No, no. The grapes aren't
dangerous, Eric.
Seriously, where are the grapes?
Don't worry. He's doing great.
We're right on schedule.
Ah, gettin' dizzy! Aah!
Ohh! Ohh!
Ohh!
I'm okay!
The concrete broke my fall.
Definite bruise.
Now explain this again.
I'm supposed to climb in
to a small, dark space
and sleep for six months?
Yes, that's what bears do.
It's called hibernation.
Sounds more like depression.
Wait, how do I eat?
Well, you don't eat.
What you do is, uh,
you eat a lot during the summer,
and that lasts you
throughout the whole winter.
Where do I go
to the bathroom?
Well, there's no going
to the bathroom.
What?
You're kidding.
I'm serious. What you do is,
a week before you hibernate,
you start eatin' things
like dirt and moss
and hair and grass, and it forms
a big, big plug in your, um,
it plugs up your -- your, um,
well, you know.
It blocks my butt?
Yeah, blocks it all up
with this big, nasty, hairy plug
of hair and grass.
Big, nasty plug.
Whoa, wait.
So you want me to sleep
for six months
with a big cork in my butt?!
Yeah, that's the idea of it.
Okay, goodbye!
- Hey, Archie!
- See ya later.
- Archie, come back here! Archie!
- Nope, I'm gone. See ya!
- Hey, headin' South?
- Archie, listen,
nobody's gonna pick up
a hitchhikin' bear.
Look, I'll split the gas and sit
in the back with the kids.
Come on, now, Archie.
Stop it.
Sorry, doc.
This isn't workin' out.
I almost drowned.
Ava doesn't like me.
Hey, I'm sick and tired of
your complaining, Archie, okay?
Look up in this tree.
What do you see, huh?
- Bird.
- Right.
A bird in his home.
And on the branch below him,
there's a squirrel in his home,
and down there by the fence
is a little rabbit
in his home.
All these animals
are depending on you.
Okay, you can do this.
Just listen to your inner bear.
Okay, just trust him.
He'll tell you what to do.
Just trust him, Archie.
Come on.
Okay, but I gotta tell you,
my inner bear has a problem
with the butt plug.
All right, that's it.
I'm gonna show you what happens
to animals who don't have
a home. Come on.
Hello, Clarice.
Uh, doc, this isn't really
necessary.
It's time for a little
tough love. Come on.
Looky here.
What's the matter, boy?
Couldn't make it
on the outside?
- Hey.
- Come on in, powder puff.
- Go on in there.
- What? What? Why?
There's a couple of bears inside
that wanna meet you. Go.
- Come on.
- I'll just sit over on that side
of the cell.
All right.
I'm tired of this madness.
Aw, don't be scared.
- I'll bite you!
- Yes. Dolittle. Oh, hi, honey.
Don't like to hunt or fish?
Do know what I would give to be
out there in the forest
instead of in this dump?
- God. Doc!
- Whoa.
Do I hear someone talkin'?
- No, no.
See, that's the problem
with kids today -- no respect.
Kid thinks he knows my life.
I think he needs us
to teach him a lesson.
- No, no, I just...
- I'm gonna give him a bear hug.
Get over here, let me give you
a bear hug.
Get on over here, tiny.
No, actually,
it's going quite well.
Yes, I think I finally got
this under... Control.
Hey, Lisa, let me call you
right back.
Doc, apparently everyone
in this place loves musicals.
I'm kidding.
I get it. I'll try harder.
Meanwhile, while the cat's away
the mice will play.
And by mice, I mean teenagers.
- Are your eyes still closed?
- Yes.
Here they come.
You did all this?
- Well...
- Okay, boys. This is it.
Remember what the doc said?
If this punk tries
anything fresh,
we let him have it.
Capisce?
I got wings, legs, tacos,
whatever.
Taco?
Did somebody say "taco"?
No, no, blend in!
Blend in!
You're gonna blow our cover!
Charisse, there's somethin'
I've really been meanin' to do
ever since we got out here.
Oh, really? What's that?
This.
- Now!
- Mwah!
Ew!
He French-kissed me! Blech!
Now that
worked out nicely.
The drinks are on me,
Jenny.
Meanwhile the doctor gave
Archie and me
some lessons of our own.
Could you leave
a little for me?
Because technically it is my --
Just a thought.
Hey! What's goin' on here?
I've been so blessed,
I feel I should give back
to the hot lady dog.
No, look, you don't have
to put up with that.
Hey, get outta here! Ha!
Go. Ha!
That is one hot fox.
What's the matter
with you two, huh?
Don't you know
that every female
is looking for
the strongest male?
But what about personality?
I'm gonna die a virgin.
Look, shut up and listen.
The strongest male
is called the Alpha male.
Now the Alpha
is the big boss.
He wants everybody to know
he's the boss male.
You have to be him --
The boss of all the males.
The Alpha male.
You have to learn how to --
How to walk like
the Alpha male.
- Walk the walk.
That's right, and talk
the Alpha male talk.
I'm still on the walk.
So it's about
power and respect.
It's about pure, unchecked,
uncompromised
testosterone-driven
male power.
John, didn't I ask you
to line the garbage pails?
You line 'em your damn self,
woman!
- What?
I'm so sorry, honey.
I was talkin' to the animals.
I got a little riled up.
I was teaching 'em something.
Stop messing with
those animals
and go and get us
something to eat.
Okay, I'm on my way. Gonna get
the food right now, honey.
- Go.
- On my way.
Way to go, Alpha male.
Talk the talk.
- Shut up!
- Who are you telling to shut up?
I wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to them.
I was talking to the animals.
I'm going to get the food.
You sure you don't want
another one of these things?
No, I'm fine.
Okay.
I got a question for you,
Archie.
Let's say you spend your whole
life in show business, right?
What's gonna be
your big finish?
Every act has
to have a big finish.
Big finish? Check it out.
"San Francisco bee" ==
"the best thing
about Archie's act is
when it's finished."
No, I mean in life,
you know?
Who you gonna share
your success with?
Your hopes and your dreams
and your fears and failures?
I'll tell you what.
Everything I do
wouldn't mean anything
if I didn't have my wife
and kids to go home to.
Sometimes I do get
very lonely.
- I've never been in love.
- Okay, this is your big chance.
You know, I think Ava
really likes you.
What. Did -- what --
Did she say something?
What'd she say?
Well, you know,
you gotta learn
to read
between the lines sometimes.
She loves me? I knew it!
Hey, let's not get carried away.
All right, Archie?
I feel like
I'm about to burst.
So this is what love
feels like, right?
Oh. Or maybe
it's the marshmallows.
Yeah, I think it's
the marshmallows
'cause you ate
a whole bag of 'em.
Doc, tomorrow you're gonna
see a brand-new bear.
You know what, Archie? I think
I'm gonna call it a night.
Don't go. It's a little scary
out here for me.
Just... Can you stay here
till I fall asleep?
Okay. I'll wait till you
fall asleep, then I'm leaving.
Hey, doc?
Yes.
Um, can you leave
that light on?
Okay. Light stays on.
I'll keep these here, okay?
Night, Archie.
Night, doc.
If you want a marshmallow,
you just gotta ask me, okay?
Look out, Ava!
There's a new Archie in town!
Oh, yeah, that feels good!
Feel it comin'.
Feel the burn!
Feel the wind.
Feel the muscle cramp!
Ow! Aah! Ow!
Come on, Archie.
Don't quit.
Dig deep. Come on.
Let's go. Come on!
I think
I pulled my butt muscle.
Ouch. It stings.
My butt stings.
Here, could you rub my butt?
Could you rub it, please?
Rub my butt.
Back here, rub my butt.
Please, rub my butt.
Doc finally realized he was
never gonna make Archie
fast enough or strong enough
to impress Ava,
but maybe -- maybe he could
make him sweet enough.
Wow. How could anybody be
so beautiful?
Why don't you go down there
and tell her that?
Uh, I don't know. I...
Oh, my...
What is that?
Oh, that's Sonny.
That's her little bear friend.
She told me about him.
But he's a kodiak bear.
Hey, don't get discouraged, man.
Listen, you can win her over.
The key
to winning a woman over
is you just figure out
what she likes.
- Like, take my wife...
- Please!
Hey, don't do that.
This is serious.
I'm sorry.
My wife, she --
She likes to be surprised.
You mean like jumping out
the bushes, screaming?
No, nothing like that.
They like romance.
Do something romantic,
something that says,
"I'm thinking about you
all the time.
You're always on my mind,"
you know?
Wow, that's really nice.
You do stuff like that
all the time?
I used to.
But lately I've been,
you know, all...
You know caught up in this,
so I guess
I'm a little
out of practice.
My candles, my fruit,
my cheese, wine. Perfect.
What are you doing?
Oh, hey, honey.
I'll tell you what
I was doing right now.
This is -- it's all
about you tonight, baby.
Yes. I sent the children
off to the movies,
and the bear is camping
in the woods.
We're all alone.
Oh, yes. All alone.
One second.
No, you cannot see me.
I am at one with the couch.
I am blended perfectly,
interwoven into every fiber.
I... Whoops!
- Come on.
I can give you some pointers.
- Found him.
No more intrusions.
Come on, it ain't no fun if
the homies can't see nothin'.
Now where were we?
Well, you were thinking
a few candles and some wine
would make up for ignoring me
for the last few days.
I'm sensing
a little resistance,
and I took that
into consideration.
I know something
you won't be able to resist.
Is this our wedding song?
That's not fair.
Is this the first thing you ever
danced to as Mrs. dolittle?
The show is about to start.
What show?
It is. It truly is.
Oh, he is so good.
Let me tell you. He scratched
my belly the other day.
My leg went crazy.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Apparently, he's truly,
truly in love with her.
Hey, doc, give her some garbage.
Chicks like garbage.
How about planting a little
sugar on Dr. d's lips, huh?
I think I can do that.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hmm.
- Go, doctor! Go, doctor!
- Oh!
Aah!
He broke her.
Hey, get outta here,
all of you!
Aw!
This ain't no peep show.
But this is really helpful.
I'm learnin' a lot. Truly.
Just get outta here.
We'll discuss it tomorrow.
Uh-oh. Busted.
You're gonna discuss what
tomorrow?
Well...
Well, I was...
I was... Well, baby,
why don't we just...
Why don't we just pick it up
where we left off, huh?
- Baby?
- Hmm?
Why don't you sleep
on the couch?
Uh, wait,
what'd she say, doc?
She said that
she loves me so much,
I get to sleep on the couch.
You're the man.
Yes, I'm the man.
I'm the man on the couch.
Psst! Hey, doc,
homeo's on the move.
His hormones are raging.
There he goes.
Hold it.
I was only goin'
to the bathroom. Uhh!
You can hold it.
I know that trick.
Hey, baby.
Hi. What's wrong
with your voice?
You're lookin' mighty fine.
So why don't you plant some of
that sugar over here on my...
On Archie the...
Oh! Oh, no.
Is that our song?
Um...
Whoa! Aah!
Ow! Hard ground! Back.
You should maybe learn how
to climb trees, truly!
That's a bruise!
Hey, come on out of there,
Archie.
Never!
Look, I'm sure
it wasn't that bad.
It was the most humiliating
thing I've ever done!
And I once rode a unicycle
in a tutu! A tutu! God!
Okay, I understand,
but we can fix this.
We just have to work
a little harder.
No, I'm just gonna stay here
and hibernate.
Tell him to stay in there.
We'll make our own bear suit.
No, Archie's fine.
Good, 'cause we were wondering
would it be all right
if every animal
in the whole entire forest
stays with you next week?
All right, Archie,
I'm not playin' anymore.
I want you to come out here
right now, you big coward!
Uh, excuse me, who are you
calling a coward?
You. I'm calling you
a coward.
You're a big coward
for quitting like this!
- Oh, it's hard.
- You know what hard is, Archie?
My wife is mad at me!
My daughter's mad at me,
and I'm spending
my vacation with a pizza boy
who greets you by saying.
"Yo, Dr. d, whassup?"
Now I'm standing here, listening
to a big, furry baby crying,
telling me he wants to quit
'cause it's too hard!
Well, Ava laughed at me.
Oh, boo-hoo.
"Ava laughed at me.
I love her and I need her
and she laughed at me!"
You know somethin'?
You don't even deserve Ava.
Why should Ava have to spend
the rest of her life
with a coward like you?
Hey, don't poke the bear,
buddy.
Well, I didn't poke a bear.
Because if I poked a bear,
a bear would be maulin' me,
so I don't know what I poked,
but it sure as hell
ain't no bear!
- Hey, I'm warnin' you.
- Oh, yeah? And I'm pokin' you.
- Hey, stop it!
- Fine. Poke, poke, poke!
All right, that's it! Uhh!
Archie, it hurt.
Hey, that felt good.
Bearlike.
Hey, Archie, you know what?
You're beyond my help.
You just take your ass
back to the circus!
A bear? Whoo-hoo!
I'm a bear!
I'm the Alpha bear!
Bears say "grr," right?
What happened to you?
Archie!
I, you know...
Potter called.
He wants to make a deal.
Just listen to what
he has to say.
It's for you, madame.
- Thanks.
- So, does Sonny bring you fish?
No, not a fish.
Usually about a hundred.
A hundred? Wait. No.
He can't carry that many.
Okay, but does Sonny tell you
that you have the most
beautiful eyes he's ever seen?
Does he promise to fill your
life with love, poetry, laughs?
No. No. Mostly he just asks me
when I think I'll be in heat.
Prince charming, huh?
Yeah.
So when is --
When is that?
Do you wanna go for a walk?
With you or alone?
- With me.
- Okay.
This isn't a walk.
We're running.
Why do we always
have to run?
Yup, there was love in the air.
Be the man. Be the man.
Be... The... Man.
Hey, now you listen to me.
Yeah, that's right.
You're in my house now.
Yeah, my house.
Also my house.
All these... Are...
My houses.
Hey, you're a lucky girl,
you know that? Yeah.
You're the lucky one, not me.
You. Yeah.
Hey, hey, you wanna go out
with me tonight?
- Or would that be good, or...
- Hey, wait a minute.
What do you think
you're doing?
Who? Who, me? No.
I'm not doing anything.
I'm just, you know,
assuming the position.
Hey, you marked my tree.
Oh, no, I would never do that.
I would never mark --
Mark your tree. I don't even
know what those words mean.
I drank a lot of water.
I'll tell you something
about water --
It goes right through me.
Come on, it smells like
lemonade.
- Oh, yeah. I see your point.
- Oh. Ahh.
Yeah, yours is
very, very strong.
It's like -- like ammonia.
I'm actually getting dizzy,
to tell you the truth.
Come on, let's beat it.
We're leaving.
Well, you two are going?
Well, have fun.
Have fun. You make
a very handsome couple.
God, I hate myself.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
You know, bears have died
trying to reach that hive.
Well, if you want it,
you got it.
Oh, please,
don't even think about it.
- That's not funny.
- No, I'm gonna get it for you.
Archie, I'm serious. Don't.
It's too dangerous.
- Okay.
- Promise me.
Okay. I like you, Ava.
I like you, too, Archie.
Aw. What are you girls
doin' over here?
Sonny, don't.
Beat it, circus boy.
- Sonny.
- Oh, you keep your yap shut.
Ha! Your charm is matched
only by your odor.
And what does that mean?
Oh, that just means
you're a malodorous ignoramus.
- It's nothing, really.
- What is he sayin'?
I'm confused. Now I don't like
bein' confused.
Yeah, he really doesn't.
Really? Well, you'd think
he'd get used to it, huh?
Let's go, Ava.
Tryin' to confuse me.
Ava, don't go. Look, maybe
you can do better than me,
but don't do worse.
I thought you liked me.
- Of course I do!
- Come on, Ava.
But you'll always be
a city bear,
and I need more than that.
city bear.
Great.
Should we, uh, put all our cards
on the table?
Of course.
This bear you brought up here
has as much likelihood
of making little bear babies
as Riley here.
Ain't gonna happen.
On the other hand,
thanks to you,
I'm not exactly drowning
in favorable publicity.
So here's my offer.
I will set aside 10 acres,
turn it into a sanctuary.
You can bring all your little
animal buddies there.
Plus you'll be saving face.
You won't have to admit
you failed.
You don't look like a fool.
Look,
10 acres is ridiculous.
That's the offer.
The deadline is Wednesday
at 12 noon.
Let me be clear.
At 12:01,
we'll be sending in
every logger,
every piece of
logging equipment we've got.
By Friday, there won't be
a tree standing.
I need to run this
by my wife.
Excellent idea. There's
a pay phone in the back.
Excuse me.
Calling the wife.
Always a sign of weakness.
Yeah.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Hey, Johnny.
What are you doing here?
Doc, I know what to do.
I got my big finish!
Look, come in here, quick.
All right.
Hey, I don't think
I'm allowed in here.
Okay, listen.
I gotta tell you,
this thing is over.
I'm just sorry I dragged you
into all of this.
I'm gonna have to get you
an audition in Vegas
or something, you know, 'cause
these guys offered me a deal,
and it's the best I can do.
No, no, the best you can do
is not give up on me, doc.
Come on, you told me.
"Listen to your inner bear."
- Remember?
- I don't know, Archie.
Look,
I know how I can win Ava!
Okay. I know I'm nuts
or something,
but I'm gonna give it
another shot.
- I'll give you one more chance.
- Yes!
- Okay, let me get over there.
Uh-oh! Uh-oh!
Uh-oh! What?
What's the problem?
- Ice cream's acting up.
- What ice cream?
I got depressed after Sonny
and Ava, and I went on a bender.
And by the second gallon
I realized
I'm in love with Ava
and this ice cream called
"cherry Garcia."
Hey, don't you dare
throw up on me.
Oh! That's not where
it's gonna come out. Ohh!
Wait, wait, wait. Watch it.
You gotta do that,
sit down on the toilet.
I can't hold it!
Hey, wait a second!
No, you gotta lift
the lid up first.
Oh! This is not gonna be
big enough! Oh, boy!
You'll be fine.
Just sit there.
- Oh!
- You sit there.
I'm gonna keep guard outside.
- You just take care
what you gotta take care of.
- I don't think it's --
Hey, how you doing?
I'll be with you in a second.
I'm gonna take care
of business.
Sure. Who are you talking to
in there?
I'm talking to myself.
I was, you know,
sometimes you gotta
coax it down.
- Right.
- Give myself a little...
Sphincter a little pep talk.
Excuse me. Come on down, you.
- Oh, my God!
- I gotta stay in here with you.
- Okay.
- Let me get the window open
or something.
- This is crazy!
- Don't do nothing
till I get the window open.
- Uh-oh!
- The window only opens
a little bit.
That's not gonna be enough.
That's not gonna be --
Oh! You're doin' it, aren't you?
- There she goes!
- Wow.
Whoa, it's worse than --
-it's worse than
I imagined it would be.
- Whoo!
Archie!
Oh! Archie!
You just had ice cream?
- Yes!
- That's not just ice cream.
Archie!
- Ah, whoo!
- Oh, Archie.
- Oh, it ain't that bad.
Come on. Whoo!
Gentlemen, uh, no deal.
Thanks for your time.
Hmm? Was that me?
Can you hear me, pepito?
Stop staring at me.
You're giving me a complex.
I'm trying to blend.
Well, if you can hear me,
can you change
to the color of this table?
What do you think
you're doing?
I think he understands me.
Well, if he understood me,
I'd tell him how sick I am
of all these stupid animals.
Oh, that really hurt.
Well, if you can understood me,
I'd tell you to do something
about those dandruff flakes.
It look like Christmas in July.
I hate this place.
So young, so angry.
Damn that rap music.
- Hey.
So? How'd it go?
Well, I told Potter no deal.
Well, I thought it wasn't
working with Archie.
Well, Archie's got an idea.
He thinks he can win Ava over,
so I'm gonna see
this thing through.
So that means we're stuck here?
Oh.
- Charisse.
- Hey, charisse.
Hey. Charisse.
Hey, it's a long walk
back to the city.
- Hmm.
- Hey, we're not getting
along too good, are we?
I wanna go home.
I wanna go home, too.
We're going home,
but there's something else
that's bothering you, isn't it?
I'm not saying
it's all your fault.
Maybe it's my fault.
Maybe it's a phase or something
that you're going through,
but something's bothering you.
Okay, and your mother thinks
you got a problem,
and you're not telling us
about it.
No.
You sure? There's nothin'
bothering you?
- I'm sure.
- Charisse.
- I'm fine, dad.
- Okay. Now, 'cause you know,
I'm not saying you do have
a problem,
but if you do have a problem,
we always --
We work things out, right?
- Right.
You cool?
Cool.
All right.
But your mother was
a little worried and I was --
- Tell her I'm fine.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Dad?
- Yes? Yes.
I knew it. I knew something
was bothering you.
What is it?
Come on, talk to me.
Come on. Talk to me, really.
You know, daddy to daughter.
Break it down.
And you can cry.
Whatever. We cry together
if that's...
What is it?
- Nothing.
- Stop.
Must be the mountains
messing me up, 'cause...
I'm fine.
- You sure you're all right?
- Mm-hmm.
She's all right!
You have
your little space.
- I'll be in the house.
- All right.
Okay.
Talking time's done.
It's time to be bold for Ava.
He's goin' after the hive!
- Who?
- Archie.
- Archie, you idiot. Jeez.
Boy, this cliff's a lot higher
than I remember.
Bye-bye, species.
So this is your big plan,
huh?
Archie, you get back here
right now! Come back in!
No way, doc.
I'm gonna do this or die tryin'.
That bear is one bad mother.
Archie, what are you doing?
Archie, you get back in here
right now!
Come back here!
Stop playing.
I don't think I'm gonna win Ava
by eating a bunch of worms.
I'm never gonna be more
woodsy than Sonny.
I have to show her how much
she means to me.
Yeah, and if you fall,
it's gonna prove
that you're stupid and dead,
Archie!
What's goin' on around here?
Oh, the circus boy's got
a new trick!
Quiet, Sonny.
- Okay, I got it, I got it.
- That log ain't gonna hold him.
And I know logs.
Okay. Whoa!
Don't move, Archie!
Don't move!
- Careful. Careful!
- I'll buy you the honey.
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Break. Break.
- This was not a good idea.
- Archie, get down!
I'm fine! Oh, oh! Bees.
Hold still!
I'll try to talk to 'em.
Work something out.
Don't you move!
- They're stinging me!
- Oh, no, don't sting.
Don't sting! Guys...
Hey, bzz, bzz! Bzz!
I can't see! They're stinging.
Get away from me! Get away!
- Attack!
No, no, hey, stop!
- Defend the hive!
- Hey, Archie!
- Get the little guy!
- Little guy!
- Protect the hive!
- Attack!
Banzai!
- Banzai!
Archie! Archie! Hey! Hey!
- Archie!
- Archie, get back in here!
Jump, circus boy.
Go suck a salmon.
Ava, I got it for you!
Good job, Archie!
Way to go, Archie.
Yeah! You did it!
Yeah!
That kid's got moxie.
I love him.
Okay. Okay, what's the matter
with you, huh?
What did you do something
like that for, huh?
Are you crazy?!
I could have got that hive
if I wanted it.
Come on, Ava,
before I get mad.
Sonny, we're not workin' out,
so take a hike.
Honey?
Yeah, babe. What's up?
No, I meant
would you like more honey?
- Oh, no, I'm good.
- Okay.
So, ready to talk about
preserving the species?
Well, we could talk.
Or you could count to a hundred
and come and get me.
Okay. Counting. Great.
Um, 1, 2...
1, 2, 3...
That's impressive.
He's really counting.
Come on, focus, focus.
Uh, 1...
Maybe I should stay in the open.
1, 2, 10, "g," "h," "p."
Green, orange, fish...
- Pace yourself. Not so fast.
- 1, 2, 3, 10...
Uh, 5-teen. Okay! 100!
Ow! What's happenin' now?
- Daddy.
- Hey.
Daddy's back.
What is it?
What happened?
It's Archie.
Okay, folks,
let's move it back now.
We got
a wild animal comin' through.
Wild animal comin' through.
I know you've all seen the show
"when animals attack."
Have you seen when animals
wake up and attack?
Now, there's nothing
more dangerous
than a half sedated,
half unsedated bear.
They have big, sharp teeth
and claws...
Excuse me, I'm Dr. dolittle.
What happened in here?
Oh, well, he broke down
the back door,
and then we found him
ransacking the kitchen.
- No.
- Yeah.
Sorry, Dr. dolittle.
I was rootin' for ya.
All right, let's move it out!
Shaw's over! Let's go.
Hey, Archie, it's me.
What happened?
Eh. I was so close, doc.
It came out of nowhere,
and...
Are you ready to save
the forest?
The good news is we're setting
aside 10 acres of forest.
We're calling it
the Dr. dolittle
wildlife sanctuary.
We're very pleased about that.
Ah, speak of the devil.
Dr. dolittle,
can we ask you a few questions?
You know, you think you've
won this thing, Riley,
but you haven't.
Fine. We'll just level
your forest and call it a tie.
Thanks very much, folks.
That's it for today. Thank you.
If only I had an eyewitness.
Did anybody see what happened?
Yeah. We got one problem.
He's a friggin' weasel.
Oh, really? What'd he do?
No, I mean he's an actual
friggin' weasel.
Hey, weasel,
the doctor's here.
Okay, you know what?
That's Mr. weasel.
Hey, well, Mr. weasel, did you
see what happened to the bear?
Ooh, the big scary bear.
Did I see what happened?
Did you see anything or not?
Okay, here's the deal.
You give me that
shiny wristwatch of yours,
and I'll tell you
what you need to know.
- You're such a weasel.
- Oh, thank you.
Look, Potter's people
set Archie up. I got a witness.
An animal? You can't
offer them to evidence.
Well,
you got any better ideas?
Well, I'll stall for time.
Maybe we'll get
a private investigator.
Those trucks are ready to roll.
They're gonna ship Archie
and ship him off to a zoo
in Mexico.
John, if you go
on the witness stand,
Riley is gonna tear you
to shreds.
- Well, what do I have to lose?
- Your reputation.
Look, I don't care.
I'm not giving up on
those animals this easy,
not without a fight.
Excuse me.
Your honor, we admit
it was a setback,
but we would like one more week
to rehabilitate the bear.
Might I suggest perhaps counsel
would like to admit
the animal
into the Betty Ford clinic?
Or the yogi bear clinic.
What if I could prove
the entire thing was a setup?
That would be
a very serious allegation.
Do you intend
to present evidence?
We have an eyewitness.
Your honor, can I address
the court just for a minute?
Go ahead.
Sir, we have an eyewitness
who'll testify
that they heard a gunshot,
then they saw a truck backing up
to the area
where the shot was fired.
Is that witness here
in the courtroom?
No, not in the courtroom
with us because, um,
he's, um...
He's a weasel.
Order.
Your honor, I know this --
This seems very unreasonable,
but I can talk to animals,
and one of them did come forward
with this information, sir.
Your honor,
if it pleases the court,
I have no problem
allowing Dr. dolittle or counsel
the opportunity
to question the eyewitness.
I would just ask
for a brief recess
so that I have opportunity
to get a camera.
I'd like a snapshot of
the animal being sworn in.
That's enough.
Does the weasel need immunity?
Because certainly
we could provide
animal protection programs.
That's enough.
Dr. dolittle,
I will not allow you
to make a mockery
of my courtroom.
The deadline has passed.
Motion to extend denied.
That's a shame.
You hate to see it.
Uh, Dr. dolittle, up here.
Dr. dolittle, can you
tell us what the weasel said?
Hey, doc, okay.
Come to get me out?
Um... Sort of.
Sort of?
What do you mean, "sort of"?
Well, I couldn't really prove
your story, Archie,
- so they, um...
- What? They what?
They think you're too dangerous
to be set free, so...
Yeah? What?
They sold you
to a Mexican circus.
Ay, chihuahua.
Archie, I am --
I'm so sorry.
For what?
For everything. You know,
dragging you out here,
putting you through
all this stuff, giving you hope.
I feel like
I ruined your life.
Ruined my life?
Doc, you gave me a life.
You're the one who taught me
about love,
and no one can ever
take that away from me.
Hey, charisse.
What are you doing
down here?
Mom wanted me to tell you
that her motion for an appeal
has been denied.
Well, we knew it was
a long shot anyway.
Archie, at least you'll be back
in show business.
Yeah, that's not what I want
anymore. I just want Ava.
I know you want Ava.
Well, maybe I wasn't meant
to be loved.
Everybody is meant to be loved.
That's right.
Everybody is meant...
Charisse.
Oh, my God.
Charisse, since when?
Couple of weeks now.
At first
it was kind of fuzzy,
but, uh...
Now it's really clear.
And this is what you've been
keeping from us, right?
I didn't wanna say anything,
dad,
because I didn't wanna
become a freak.
No, you're not gonna
Not at all.
Hey, look, when it started
happening to me,
I got scared, too. You're just
looking at it the wrong way.
This is a good thing.
How?
Look at all the good
that's come out of it already.
What good?
Look at us, like this, huh?
How about this? Huh?
Mmm!
Hey, guys, now I know what I've
been missing -- a family.
I guess that's something
I'll never have.
Dad, you gotta help him.
Isn't there something
that we can do?
And it's not just him.
I mean, it's all the animals.
There's so many of 'em.
Yeah,
there are so many of 'em.
You guys have given up,
haven't you?
Hey, what am I gonna do?
I'm 6 years old.
I'm not a young beaver
no more.
Besides, we've been livin'
in this forest how long?
About a hundred years we've been
shakin' down this forest, boss.
So we had a good run.
Look, I tried to do this
by myself, but I can't.
So if you guys wanna save
your homes,
you're gonna have to help me.
And whether or not
you believe it,
you guys have
enormous untapped power.
I'm serious.
Whenever talk about the best
of the best,
it's always
an animal expression.
You got a heart like a lion
or you're as strong as an ox.
He's got eyes like an eagle
or he can move swift
like a gazelle.
Or you stink like a skunk!
- What?
- Sorry about that, man.
I'm just trying to
make my point here.
What I'm trying to say is
we can do this! We can do it!
Just don't give up
without a fight.
Let the word go out from sicily
to seaworld --
The trucks don't move,
capisce?
- The beaver's right!
- Yeah!
All right! Yeah!
Yeah!
Hey, kids, I'm gonna have
to ask you to move!
- No!
- No?
Listen, don't start with me.
Everybody, take your positions!
Hasta LA vista, baby.
Roll 'em up!
I ain't never seen
nothing like this before.
None of them have any milk.
- What?
- All of 'em are dry.
What's wrong, Annabelle?
- Strike. Strike.
- Strike. Strike. Strike!
Here's your eggs!
You want 'em scrambled?
Strike! Strike! Strike!
Okay, let's go get the frisbee.
Come on, go get it!
Oh!
Strike. Strike. Strike.
- Come on, give me that leash.
- Strike, strike, strike!
Whoa!
Hey, Archie, all the animals
are working together.
You'll be out of here
in no time.
It's ridiculous.
Animals can't organize.
You may wanna take a look
at this for yourself then.
All over the world,
animals have organized.
They're striking
in Paris, Texas.
In Paris, France,
in Brooklyn, in Mexico,
and in Canada.
I'm sure I'm gonna regret this
in the morning,
but maybe you should talk
with dolittle.
And what?
Give in to a bunch of beasts
and lower life forms?
I took on the democrats!
I can take on
a bunch of animals.
Charge!
Oh, no!
Go on!
- Come on!
- Watch it.
- Go on, beat it.
- Retreat!
Go on. Huh!
Medic!
Organized.
We have two bogeys bearing
Alpha, tango, niner.
We are locked on target,
squad leader.
- Do you hear something?
- Commence bombing.
Roger that, sir.
Well done, men.
I got your wing, iceman.
Party ain't over yet.
I want the short one.
Sir?
Don't make
any sudden moves.
Gotcha.
Aah!
Attack! Lock and unload!
Poops away!
Firing number two.
Let's return
to base and reload.
Sir, you, uh,
- you've locked the...
- What?
You've locked the door, sir!
You might wanna...
Sir!
- I think you should run.
- I'm an attorney.
- I was --
- Yeah.
- I'm not with him.
- Run.
There he is again!
Get the little guy!
- Banzai!
Not the face!
No, please. No, no. I'm sure
we can work something out.
I'm just reaching for my phone.
I'm gonna call Dr. dolittle.
Oh, whoa, whoa,
no sudden movements,
or I'm gonna bite you
in the cannolis.
Uh, hello. The number for
Dr. John dolittle, please?
Not Stuart little. Dolittle.
Dolittle. Oh, Mr. Potter.
How are you, sir?
Oh, I could be better.
I'm here
with a couple of your friends.
I know you can't
possibly believe
that animals are organized.
Uh, well, you know, I don't know
what to think anymore.
I'll tell you what. Let's put
our cards on the table.
I will be more than happy
to set up a meeting
between you and these animals
so you can work out
your problems.
- What?!
- Hey, look, it's the only way
you're gonna be able
to save face
you won't have to admit
you were wrong,
and you can
get out of this thing
without looking like
an idiot.
Okay, okay, look, anything.
Just - just call 'em off.
Okay, all right, listen.
Put the raccoon on the phone.
He wants to speak to you.
Make it short.
Hello.
Yeah.
No, no, no,
I got it under control.
Hey, we'll call youse back.
First off, let me say that
I am here only as a mediator
and these negotiations
will be between Mr. Potter
and the representatives
of the united animals
of the forest local 534.
Yeah, let's come to order.
- This is my new proposal.
- All right.
What's the stipulations, doc?
What kind of territory
we lookin' at?
It's only, uh, 12 acres here.
It's 12 acres.
I got your 12 acres
right here, pal.
Hey, they like it.
I'll give you somethin'
you like. Like this.
I think that's a "no."
Or "hell, no," maybe.
Meanwhile,
the strike kept growing.
Even the pros were getting in
on the act.
The last few runners left
to load now for
one of the biggest spectacles
of the year --
It's derby time.
Last horse is in, gates closed.
And away they go!
Hell, no, we won't go!
- Hell, no, we won't go!
- Run your own stupid race.
- Come on.
- You try running a mile.
Don't even think about reaching
for that whip, shorty.
Ladies and gentlemen, sham...
This is shamu!
Nah, I don't feel like jumpin'
through any hoops today.
Any of you guys?
Nope, nope, not me. Not today.
I just ate. Unh-unh.
Mr. Potter, I hope
we have a deal now.
- All right!
- All right, doc!
- Yeah!
- Good job.
Taught him everything
he knows.
Vive le bear! Vive le Archie!
Vive le docteur! Ha!
Come on, give me a bear hug.
Come on.
No, absolutely not, Archie.
You're not leavin' here
until you get a bear hug.
All right, all right, give you
a hug. Just a little one.
- Come on.
- Okay, all right, that's it.
All right, Archie.
Archie!
You're crushing my spine.
Bye-bye. Drive safe now.
Buckle up.
- Hey, Archie, you in there?
- What?!
Hey, doc.
Hey, man, I just stopped by
to say so long.
Oh, thanks for everything.
You are quite welcome.
Archie, I'm ready.
Ah, she's in heat.
Excuse me, doc.
Gotta go save the species.
Ohh.
Go do your thing, Archie.
Yeah, Archie. Archie!
Oh, Archie.
Yeah, it was quite a summer.
Hey, doc!
Hey, lucky,
what are you doing?
What am I doing?
Hmm. Let me phrase it this way.
Ahh.
You, too, huh?
And charisse and the doc
were closer than ever.
Oh, come on. Cheer up, pepito.
You'll get it eventually.
No, I won't.
I will never blend in.
- I have a broken blender.
- You will blend in, trust me.
- You will blend in.
- How?
How will pepito ever blend in?
Pepito sucks.
Aah!
Look at me!
I'm blending in!
I'm invisible!
That's right. You're invisible.
Great job, honey.
Did you ever doubt me?
The blendmaster is back!
- How about that?
- I am king of the third world!
Hey, can we do
the whole house like this?
It's very feng shui!
But the best news of all came
the following spring.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Kids, come on.
Hey, hoo! Hoo!
Over here, kids! Hoo-hoo!
Over here. Okay.
Now, it's step, step,
turn, kick, step.
Papa, I thought it was step,
kick, turn, step, step.
Come on, kids.
We open in six weeks, okay?
- I thought you retired.
- Uh... I did, honey.
We're just playin'. Okay, now,
from the chorus. 5, 6, 7.